<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<comment id="2.7.1.3.3">
	<original>
	"...Since that age of imperialism, the world catastrophe of the mid 20th century has reshaped the world order to a better place. China is flouting this order now, not 100 years ago..."

See, here's the problem. Evidently, what you imagine as the "world order" is a world in which America :

-- Illegally invades, devastates and occupies countries like Iraq;

-- Subverts the Internet's basic infrastructure in order to engage in mass surveillance on (literally) everyone in the entire world;

-- Maintains an enormous arsenal of deliverable thermonuclear weapons, occasionally threatening their first use against enemies real or imagined, who don't have any;

-- Maintains a world-wide Gulag of illegal political prisons such as Guantanamo;

-- Engages in random murder (via drone strikes, assassination raids etc.) of people who the President of the United States, on his secret, unilateral order, has marked for immediate death, without benefit of a trial;

-- Sails nuclear-armed battle fleets, just outside (and sometimes inside) the territorial waters of unfriendly nations (including China and Iran), spoiling for a fight and "daring" the country involved to take the first shot;

-- Repeatedly attempts and / or supports the violent, illegal overthrow of foreign governments, including (for example, in Venezuela, Egypt and the Gaza Strip) democratically-elected governments...

I could go on and on.

The point here is, anything that China (or Russia) has done -- certainly since the Maoist period -- pales by comparison with the United States' own, extensive list of gross violations of international law, aggression against other countries and dangerous, provocative military posturing (how about, for example, repeated violations of Chinese airspace by U.S. spy planes -- what do you suppose America would do, if Chinese aircraft routinely overflew, say, Camp Pendleton, without notice or authorization?).

So DON'T lecture ME, about "the 'world order', and how naughty old China, is 'violating' it". You are using a nonsense, laughably ethno-centric construct of unilateralist, jingoist American propaganda, to create a sham complaint against something that China has dabbled in, while the United States has sprayed all over the place. It may play well in "God's Chosen Country", but out here in the rest of the world, after we finish laughing ourselves silly upon hearing it... we get angry.


	</original>
	<cleaned>
	</cleaned>
	<entity_tagged>
	</entity_tagged>
	<summary>
	</summary>
</comment>
