<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<comment id="2.9.1.2.1.1.1">
	<original>
	"... that same Law of the Sea Convention. The one that the U.S. Navy still adheres to in spite of Congress's unwillingness to ratify..."

That's not true (for two obvious reasons : one, the U.S. Navy, by American law and the chain of command, MUST implement the policies of the U.S. government, and two, the Law of the Sea treaty is mostly about management of maritime resources, not the activities of military vessels on the high seas).

For further reference, see :

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/...

Did you REALLY think you could get away with such pathetically lame, transparently self-serving American propaganda? Sorry, squire; you're arguing in the big leagues, now, and the kind of flag-wavin' drivel that the natives lap up like Pavlov's dogs back in Topeka and Baton Rouge, doesn't cut it with non-American audiences.

Now as to China's supposed "illegal" development of offensive sea mines. I'd remind you that the one country that has done more to thumb its nose at all international conventions -- including but by no means limited to the various Hague conventions (and, significantly, the non-proliferation treaties... remember them?) -- than ANYONE else, is your nice beloved United States; so you're in a very exposed position indeed, in fatuously trying to point fingers at the Chinese (or anyone) for what they may or may not have done in trying to catch up to America's globe-encircling, nuclear-armed imperialist naval fleets.

But let's take "offensive sea mines", since you seem to be so hung up on them. Were you unaware of the following, sir?

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/...

Maybe you had better <ahem> do a bit more research before you start pompously pontificating about "those nasty Chinese sea mines".

Oh, but I FORGOT; American offensive sea mines are "good", while those used by anyone else, are "bad", because, of course, within the crazy-house "reasoning" of your nation's jingoistic, self-serving propaganda, America is an "exceptional" nation that gets to do things which would, if done by anyone else, be cause for sanctions, trials, bombing raids, and even "pre-emptive wars".

So... what's "not even funny"?

I'll tell you : Having to listen to propaganda from someone who doesn't understand that he's repeating it.


	</original>
	<cleaned>
	</cleaned>
	<entity_tagged>
	</entity_tagged>
	<summary>
	</summary>
</comment>
