<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<comment id="2.9.1.2.1.1.1.2">
	<original>
	Also, you didn't read the Hague Convention on sea mines, did you? Apologies about my previous post--I simply referred to "offensive sea mines" instead of clarifying. They are developing an arsenal of "drifting mines" that simply float in the water and don't detonate. That's disastrous for international commerce and pretty much every neutral vessel passing through the region. The Convention specifically prohibits "unanchored contact mines" that do not "become harmless [after] one hour at most." Hague Convention of 1907 No. VIII Relative to the Laying of Automatic Submarine Contact Mines, art. I, Oct. 18, 1907; Jason Reddish, Forgotten Fears Present Imminent Threats to the Maritime Shipping and Recreation Industries: The Risk Posed by the Availability of Sea Mines, 29 Tul. Mar. L.J. 125, 129 (2004); Andrew S. Erickson, Lyle J. Goldstein, & William S. Murray, Chinese Mine Warefare: A PLA Navy “Assassin’s Mace” Capability, Naval War College China Maritime Studies No. 3, at 1 (2009); A.G.Y. Thorpe, Mine Warfare at Sea--Some Legal Aspects of the Future, 18 Ocean Dev. & Int. L. 255, 263 (1987). China ratified the Convention's provisions on sea mines over a century ago because it suffered from the effects of the Russo-Japanese War, which it wasn't even part of. Howard S. Levie, Mine Warfare at Sea 28-29 (1992) (“[A] very considerable number of [Chinese] coasting trade boats, fishing boats, junks and sampans have sunk as a consequence of collisions with these automatic submarine contact mines . . . . It is calculated that from five to six hundred of [China’s] countrymen in the pursuit of their peaceful occupations have met a cruel death through these dangerous engines.”). It looks like they forgot about that experience. Anyway, I'm done with this thread. I apologize for not doing more "research."


	</original>
	<cleaned>
	</cleaned>
	<entity_tagged>
	</entity_tagged>
	<summary>
	</summary>
</comment>
