<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<comment id="20">
	<original>
	I find it depressing that this article only provides two or three paragraphs focused on the actual driver of Chinese foreign policy, that is, Chinese domestic politics.

There are two core issues which drive foreign provocations under Xi's government. First, looking at his policies from the standpoint of intraparty factionalism: Quite frankly, Xi himself is NOT popular with the PLA. He's the leading figure in a faction of the CCP which seeks to curb (to some extent, anyway) the corruption and ridiculous abuse of authority. His initiatives and campaigns span the whole party, but the PLA's leadership represents a concentration of the sort of behavior he is attempting to reign in and they therefore intensely dislike him. This is compounded by the fact that his faction has its roots in the relatively prosperous and well-educated urban classes and its leaders are mostly descendants of former Party high-ups (hence the name "Princelings"), which means that the mostly dirt-poor, rural enlisted personnel and NCO's of the PLA also dislike (perhaps "hate" is a better word) him and his faction.

Thus, the PLA represents the only center of power in the Party with the strength and cohesiveness to upend his reform agenda, or, if the generals sense that he poses an existential threat to them and their privilege, to go beyond channels and remove or sideline him entirely. His pandering to nationalist sentiments in his foreign policy is at least in part driven by his need to keep the allegiance of the army's low- and mid-ranking personnel, who are generally poorly or moderately educated and thus rabidly nationalist. If he can keep them onboard, he can thwart any attempts by the PLA leadership to scuttle his anti-corruption drives or threaten his own person and leadership, making them fear that their sword will turn in their hand if they strike a blow with it.

Secondly, from a broader societal standpoint: Chinese economic growth over the last 30 years has provided sufficient "bread and circuses" to most of the urban population to keep them onboard with the program. In short, the current Chinese social contract with the urban populace reads: "you get a continually higher standard of living, and we keep political control." This is no longer sustainable in the cities as economic growth starts to slow and the massive inequalities and structural flaws which arose in those 30 years become apparent.

Yet, even most of the urban population is still not educated particularly well, and very few are cosmopolitan or open in the sense that many Americans and most Europeans are. Pandering to their nationalist sensibilities still *works*, and in the absence of continued double-digit economic growth, it can ensure urban support for continued Party rule despite them having shuffled political liberalization to the back burner and then turning off the stove. With the Party not only being assertive abroad but also prosecuting a moderately effective (if slow) crackdown on corruption at home, it can probably ensure relative urban stability and support for or acquiescence to continued Party rule.

The rural picture is even more complicated; rural areas have seen only a fraction of the economic growth and development of urban ones, but because of that their educational systems lag severely and are much more propagandized. This means that the best ways to keep them in line are to play to their nationalist and xenophobic instincts and promote the image of the Party as a caring and kind uncle to the masses; the former is covered by Chinese belligerence abroad, especially towards traditional enemies that rural residents have been encouraged to hate by their own elders and a heavily propagandized reading of history, while the latter is fulfilled through the current anti-corruption campaigns.

In short, Chinese belligerence abroad and the resulting poor relations with the neighbors is the price that Xi has to pay to find a way of replacing rapid economic growth as the primary support for Party legitimacy. Party rule will stand or fall on its ability to control its own corruption (for which Xi needs the support of the PLA's rank and file) and keep Chinese ultranationalists contented without actually provoking a war. Thus, we have saber rattling all over the Chinese periphery, because the leadership of the Party simply do not care about foreign opinion or goodwill at present. It is a luxury they cannot afford: their entire system is balanced on a knife's edge, and with it their power, and the only people with the power to affect it live within China's borders.


	</original>
	<cleaned>
	</cleaned>
	<entity_tagged>
	</entity_tagged>
	<summary>
	</summary>
</comment>
