<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<comment id="30">
	<original>
	China is cruising for a bruising. Sure they can bully all these small countries around, but collectively and internationally this will pay sour dividends in the future in the form of plenty of bad blood, ill relations and put a drag on their economy while the demographics of their aging population will make it harder for the country to grow. They have a billion mouths to feed and they have stirred the pot of nationalism to such an extent that any reversal of their fortunes is likely to be very dangerous. They have painted themselves in a corner in the South China Sea. It's perhaps only a matter of time before something happens.

It seems the Chinese leadership must feel they are ready to resume their position as the hegemon of Asia if not the world, new Sun Emperors. They want to create a new China centric world order, throwing out the one arrived at by western powers over the centuries. Having recently visited there and worked with them for some time I know they are very self confident even if they have little to be self confident about. I saw this first had while the smog stung my eyes closed on the Bund and while watching people working night and day on huge new office towers (with out the need to find tenants to occupy them). This is still a poor country with workers walking around with tree branches fashioned as brooms to clean the streets, bicycles go down the road with couches and huge loads of Styrofoam to recycle. Instead of working with the existing system they are working to create a new one with the likes of Vladimir Putin.

Putin likes to see Russia as a great power and not the oil kleptocracy it has become where his friends shake down any successful business and steal their companies. Hitching the future of Russia to China is likely to be as successful a strategy as that of Polish Foreign Minister Beck who thought he could form an alliance with Hitler in 1939. In reality Russia could become a satellite of China or perhaps play Mussolini to Xi's Hitler. In any case, Putin is knucklehead to think Russia will not get rolled like everyone else in Beijing.


	</original>
	<cleaned>
	</cleaned>
	<entity_tagged>
	</entity_tagged>
	<summary>
	</summary>
</comment>
