<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<comment id="2.7.1.3.2.1.1.1">
	<original>
	"Really? Please find me ONE (1) parallel, undertaken by either Russia or China since World War 2, in which either of those countries engaged in something like the illegal U.S. invasion of Iraq."

They don't have to, and your asking me to find that sort of example is in and of itself an attempt to discredit by asking for an impossible standard of evidence. And I don't need Tibet or Afghanistan, though those would suffice.

Rather, I can point you, most recently, to Ukraine on the part of Russia (irredentist revanchism on the part of Putin) and to the multiple attempts on the part of the PRC to extend its economic and military control over a swath of ocean and territory which neither it nor the dynasties it bases its claims off of ever had administration or actual legal control. In both cases, the fundamental logic is the same as the U.S invasion of Iraq; the use of military invasion or coercion based on at best shaky logic or outright revanchism in order to distract from domestic crises or to generate political capital.

"-- in sharp contrast to the United States, in which the same oligopoly has been in charge literally since the Industrial Revolution.)"

As opposed to oligopolies that were, are, and will be in power in both the Russian Federation and the PRC for the forseeable future? Don't make me laugh. You are basically accusing the U.S of having barely advanced forward from the times when companies owned entire towns and deliberately kept workers in debt; much progress has been made since then, in no small part thanks to the (now dwindling) strength of unions in the U.S.

I won't call the U.S perfect--far from it, in fact; but there are no circumstances that will let me think that the PRC or Russia are somehow better or more worthy of praise merely because they victimize their own populations and neighbors' populations rather than going half-way around the world to do so. Further, at no time were the lies surrounding the Iraq War--which were swiftly revealed by an independent western press both within and without the U.S--ever as pervasive as the deliberate propaganda and outright lies surrounding Russia's campaign in Ukraine.


	</original>
	<cleaned>
	</cleaned>
	<entity_tagged>
	</entity_tagged>
	<summary>
	</summary>
</comment>
