<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<comment id="20.1.1.1.1.2.1">
	<original>
	What you're asking actually contains two separate questions, essentially, "what are the chances of a war starting by accident?" and "what are the chances of a war starting on purpose?".

The latter's simpler: the CCP knows damned well that it currently can't even defeat Japan, let alone Japan+US+allies. Thus, there are only two conditions under which China would intentionally start a war in the Western Pacific. First, if the economic climate is so horrific that losing foreign trade would change nothing anyway and the CCP needs the distraction, i.e. a Second Great Depression scenario. Secondly, if the CCP is overthrown by ultranationalists. Even a military coup wouldn't result in a war against the US and allies, as the PLA knows just as well as the CCP that they'd lose, and badly; the rabid nationalists, on the other hand, are operating under the delusion that they could win such a war.

The former is more complex; it's entirely possible that one of these incidents will end up in shooting or a collision or something else that neither side can afford to ignore if the voters/masses aren't going to throw the government out on their *sses. The most likely place for this to happen is in the Senkaku/Diaoyu Islands, because Japan is by far the most powerful of the countries sparring with China on its periphery, and the most closely integrated into the American defense umbrella, thus it's the boldest. It's also the one China dislikes most strongly, which means that China's domestic opinion won't allow the CCP to back down.

The Philippines and Vietnam are much less likely to court an incident than Japan, but unfortunately, because they're much less able to defend themselves, the Chinese are much more likely to push them into a corner where they feel they have no recourse but to back the decisions of the people on scene no matter the consequences, especially Vietnam, whose links with the US are fragile and untested, as yet.

Nonetheless, I don't rate the chances of an actual war coming out of this as being very high; the Chinese do NOT want to take on Japan or the US, which means they cannot go after Malaysia, Japan, Taiwan, or the Philippines and will soft-ball any incidents which arise to the greatest extent they possibly can. The most likely war scenario is a bilateral war between China and Vietnam which sees Vietnam swept from the seas and China's naval development kicked back 5-10 years by Vietnamese ex-Soviet submarines.


	</original>
	<cleaned>
	</cleaned>
	<entity_tagged>
	</entity_tagged>
	<summary>
	</summary>
</comment>
