<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<comment id="37">
	<original>
	At several points, French touches on Taiwan, which is the crucial weak link in "the first island chain." But, French is spectacularly remiss in leaving out of consideration the very important and portentous changes that have been occurring in the Taiwan-China relationship since Ma became Taiwan President in 2008. Taiwan has significantly been steadily moving closer to China. Correspondingly, Taipei's relationship with Washington has been gradually fading, especially during the simultaneous presidencies of Ma and Obama.

French says enough to show us that he knows that Taiwan is China's real target, but misses the important point that Taiwan is probably also China's priority, in terms of sequence. The way I see it -- Taiwan comes first; the others, China will deal with later.

In my view, much of China's current maritime bluster is a cover for an early China move to take Taiwan. In my estimation, China will sooner or later exploit a perceived crisis with Japan to effect a surprise landing of PLA troops on Taiwan, provided that there is secretly prior agreement with Kuomintang leaders, including President Ma and his top generals.

The precedent is the largely peaceful manner in which Hitler's Wehrmacht rolled into Austria in March 1938, with the active complicity of those many Austrian politicians who were either Nazis or supported the idea of union (Anschluss) with Germany. We have seen this film before, then in black-and-white but today in rich color.

PLA missiles, fighter planes and naval bases on Taiwan would break "the first island chain" and significantly degrade the strategic position of both Japan and the Philippines. China's return to Taiwan is the game changer that will effectively drive the USA out of the Western Pacific.

Although French nowhere directly touches on the top Chinese leadership's perception of President Obama, numerous points in his text tend to substantiate a presumption that President Obama made a very poor first impression during his November 2009 visit to China. This must have been so, because Premier Wen Jiabao shortly thereafter went out of his way to treat the USA President with great discourtesy at the December 2009 Copenhagen Climate Change Summit. This was an early element of China's continuing process of testing the quality of Obama's leadership.

French does believe that the top Chinese leadership perceived spectacular weakness in President Obama's policies with regard to Syria and Ukraine. However, French entirely misses the far more important point that the top Chinese leadership probably also perceive Obama to be astonishingly weak because of his very peculiar approach to Iran's race to nuclear weapons.

World leaders were amazed to see Obama unilaterally relaxing sanctions upfront, and dropping agreed Security Council resolutions demanding a total end to uranium enrichment by Iran -- while publicly pouring cold water on any expectation that the USA might perhaps eventually have to use some force to stop or delay the ayatollahs' nuclear-weapons ambitions. For example, the way in which Obama publicly deplored the possibility of a "fourth war with a Muslim country" not only enhanced the security and confidence of the Iranians, but at the same time convinced the Chinese and Russian leaders that, under Obama, the USA is well and truly just "a paper tiger," as detailed by French. Nor would world leaders have missed the way that President Obama powerfully leaned on Israel to prevent it from acting alone to attack Iran's nuclear-weapons development installations.

Result? Firstly, the continuing Russian invasions of Ukraine; and secondly, the greatly accelerated ambitions of China, as ably set out in this French article.


	</original>
	<cleaned>
	</cleaned>
	<entity_tagged>
	</entity_tagged>
	<summary>
	</summary>
</comment>
