<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<comment id="1.2.1">
	<original>
	Disagree with several of your comments. Russia is not rebuilding any Soviet empire. They are responding to the containment via NATO encroaching and US destabilizing via proxy Ukraine. Crimea is merely a return of what was always Russian, and Ukraine disintegration is natural due to corruption and its proxy status against Russia. You reap what you sow, and the Hegemon is reaping reaction to its attempts to destroy the Russian Federation.

China may be hungry for resources, but it's maritime reach is based on historical realities. The U.S. is desperate to maintain its naval hegemony, and China is nullifying that with its carrier-killer missile threat. A new Maritime Silk Road and a proposed canal through Thailand would eliminate the Straits of Malacca as a choke point the U.S. controls. Who is trying to limit who where? Its the US trying to stop China from being a true blue water naval power. The U.S. using an imperialistic Japan to torment China, Taiwan and South Korea in the Yellow Sea and East China Sea.

The 20th Century realities are gone. China and Russia will build a Eurasian market of over 3.5 billion people from the Far East and South Asia (India) to Russia and East Europe through Central Asia. This coming realty is what reduces the West and its corrupt EU, maniacal Nato, and collapsing American governmental tyranny to secondary position if they don't change from Hegemon to a multi-polar player.

Dig into the facts of the SCO, the New Silk Road, the Maritime Silk Road and look at the militarism of Abe's Japan and the use of the Philippines as proxy for the US.

China merely is the new bank for all emerging and most developing nations. A role once filled by a financially sound U.S. Now, the U.S. can only spread chaos and attempt de-stabilization to hold onto power. It's run as an empire is coming to an end. It may take ten more years, but debt will be the victor over the tyrant. The Liberals inherited the world and have destroyed it with their ideologies and wars.

Russia and China signed strategic economic and technological agreements far beyond the big gas deal. Now they are working on space, jumbo airliner, weapons, agriculture, rail, home construction, ports, bridges, pipelines, education, IT security, oil and gas and fresh water projects, food, currency, banking and finance (substitute for SWIFT and use of the Chinese credit card system). The Far East and Siberia, and Crimea and East Ukraine (now Novorossiya) are all areas of integration of Chinese and Russian development, as well as Northeast China (Heliongjiang Province) opening up to Russia projects.

Even India is getting Chinese investment for its infrastructure projects. If India wasn't so corrupt, they would have many more Chinese built ports and highways. The Chinese are going to modernize the India rail system.

The U.S. maybe thinks it can send Tweets and try to start some more color revolutions, but it has very little to offer to any but the most subservient nations. It is bringing down all its allies with debt and draconian Trade agreements. Look into TTIP and TTP and see how it colonizes any nation that joins. Pure hegemony in exchange for a nuclear umbrella and debt.


	</original>
	<cleaned>
	</cleaned>
	<entity_tagged>
	</entity_tagged>
	<summary>
	</summary>
</comment>
