<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<comment id="4.7.1.1.1.1">
	<original>
	as regards the islands of the south china sea and China's "claims to them":

http://www.prospectmagazine.co...

"When a Chinese government committee first gave Chinese names to the islands in 1935 all it did was either translate or transliterate the existing British names. In the Paracels, for example, Antelope Reef became Líng yang (the Chinese word for antelope) and in the Spratlys, North Danger Reef became B?i xi?n (Chinese for “north danger”), Spratly Island became Si-ba-la-tuo (the Chinese transliteration of the English name). The Chinese committee simply copied the British maps, errors and all. The names were then revised, twice. Scarborough Shoal, named after a British ship in 1748, was originally transliterated as Si ge ba luo in 1935, renamed Min’zhu Jiao—Democracy Reef by the nationalist Republic of China in 1947 and then given the less politically-sensitive name of Huangyan (Yellow Rock) by the communist People’s Republic of China in 1983...The story probably begins with the first Opium War in 1840 and what the Chinese now call the “century of national humiliation” that followed. China clearly suffered grievously at the hands of Western and Japanese imperialists: thousands were killed, cities were colonised and the government fell in hock to international banks. The geographer William Callahan and others have outlined how, as part of the struggle against foreign domination, nationalists and communists deliberately cultivated a sense of territorial violation to mobilise the population. From the 1900s onwards, Chinese geographers such as Bai Meichu, one of the founders of the China Geography Society, began to draw maps to show the public how much territory had been torn from away from China by the imperialists.

These “maps of national humiliation” assumed that China’s rightful territory included every former vassal that had once offered tribute to a Chinese emperor. They included the Korean peninsula, large areas of Russia, Central Asia, the Himalayas and many parts of Southeast Asia. Lines were drawn on these maps to contrast the vast domains of former empires with the country’s shrunken state. Fatefully, after the officialChinese committee had renamed the islands in the South China Sea in 1935, one of these lines was drawn around the Sea. This is what is now called the “U-shaped” or “9-dash” line encompassing 80 per cent of the Sea and all the islands within it. That cartographical accident, based on misreadings of Southeast Asian history, is the basis for China’s current claim of sovereignty.

China clearly suffered abuse at the hands of domineering foreigners but the modern state that emerged from the rubble of the Qing Dynasty and the subsequent civil wars has found solace in false memories that bear little relation to what actually happened. As any visitor to the new “Road to Revival” exhibition at the National Museum of China in Tiananmen Square will discover, this false memory syndrome is a critical ingredient in the legitimising myth of the Communist Party: that it saved the nation from humiliation.


	</original>
	<cleaned>
	</cleaned>
	<entity_tagged>
	</entity_tagged>
	<summary>
	</summary>
</comment>
