<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<comment id="5.1.2">
	<original>
	I certainly wouldn't say that China has "no soft power." Actually, I did write that at first but edited it almost immediately. Much has been written about China's attempts to cultivate soft power. At the risk of posting a TLDR reply, I'm going to quote below some excerpts from an article in Foreign Policy that I think elucidates what I mean when I say China suffers from a "lack of diplomacy and soft power".

Before I do, I just want to remark that it seems to me that much of the cheering for China around the world has not at its core an enthusiasm for Chinese culture or policy, but a desire to see an abatement of the power of the United States. This is in marked contrast to American soft power. I've lived in Turkey, a country with some of the highest disapproval rates of US foreign policy in the world. Yet everywhere I went, people were genuinely delighted to meet an American (even in Istanbul where drunkenly partying Westerners are a common annoyance). During every conversation I had about world events, I was emphatically informed that Turkish people liked Americans, even though they disliked the actions of our government.

That's soft power.

When I met my wife's cousin, a senior engineer tasked with retrofitting Istanbul's buildings for earthquake preparedness, an Herculean effort that should give some clue to his level of intelligence, he was beside himself with glee to sit down and chat with an American. My poor wife could hardly keep up the translation with all the things he wanted to say. One thing in particular stuck with me. He said that a Turk like my wife could go to America and become an American. But the Turks whose great grandparents went to Germany still aren't Germans.

That's also soft power.

People around the world watch Hollywood movies (and complain about them as much as we do, but still watch them--like we do), listen to our pop music, watch our tv shows, and read gossip about our celebrities. There's a disconcertingly huge gap in their understanding of how our society works, but nevertheless they have a direct connection with us through our culture.

Again, soft power.

Despite China's efforts to fund projects in third world countries, there's just no parallel between global attitudes toward China and the examples I cited above.

Ok, here's some more thoughts on soft power from Harvard professor Joseph S. Nye from that FP article:



The soft power of a country rests primarily on three resources: its culture (in places where it is attractive to others), its political values (when it lives up to them at home and abroad), and its foreign policies (when they are seen as legitimate and having moral authority). Much of America's soft power is produced by civil society -- everything from universities and foundations to Hollywood and pop culture -- not from the government. Sometimes the United States is able to preserve a degree of soft power because of its critical and uncensored civil society even when government actions -- like the invasion of Iraq -- are otherwise undermining it. Even China's soft-power triumphs, such as the 2008 Beijing Olympics, have quickly turned stale. Not long after the last international athletes had departed, China's domestic crackdown on human rights activists undercut its soft power gains. Again in 2009, the Shanghai Expo was a great success, but it was followed by the jailing of Nobel Peace Laureate Liu Xiaobo and screens were dominated by scenes of an empty chair at the Oslo ceremonies. China and Russia make the mistake of thinking that government is the main instrument of soft power. In today's world, information is not scarce but attention is, and attention depends on credibility. Government propaganda is rarely credible. The best propaganda is not propaganda. For all the efforts to turn Xinhua and China Central Television into competitors to CNN and the BBC, there is little international audience for brittle propaganda. As the Economist noted about China, "the party has not bought into Mr. Nye's view that soft power springs largely from individuals, the private sector, and civil society. So the government has taken to promoting ancient cultural icons whom it thinks might have global appeal." But soft power doesn't work that way. As Pang Zhongying of Renmin University put it, it highlights "a poverty of thought" among Chinese leaders.



http://www.foreignpolicy.com/a...


	</original>
	<cleaned>
	</cleaned>
	<entity_tagged>
	</entity_tagged>
	<summary>
	</summary>
</comment>
