<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<comment id="5.1.2.1.1">
	<original>
	I don't know about reading, writing, and speaking, but I'd certainly rather type in English. We don't even have to worry about diacriticals, let alone logosyllabic scripts.

But you raise an excellent point that relates to soft power. English is the global lingua franca of business and science and technology. The historical reasons why this is so are obvious. But having taught English abroad, I also think there are some intrinsic reasons why English accounts for 60% of all foreign language learning in the world.

English has a reputation as one of the more difficult languages in the world to master because of non-phonetic spellings, idioms, homonyms, homophones, homographs, lack of any central authority over usages, and the sheer number of words, including archaic, technical, and scientific terminology, among other reasons.

This depth of vocabulary is not a weakness, it's a strength. It makes English more efficient. When the same block of text is issued in multiple languages, the English version is nearly always the shortest one since there's usually a word that perfectly conveys the meaning, rather than the wordy work-arounds other languages often have to employ.

Despite English's reputation for being tough to master, it's also considered one of the easiest languages to start learning and using at a beginner/intermediate level. Here are some reasons why English is considered one of the easiest languages to learn (but not master):

Verb conjugation: A typical French verb has more than fifty endings that must be learned. A regular English verb has four.

Irregular verbs: It would take less than a page to list all irregular forms of all irregular verbs in English, as compared with sixteen pages for Spanish. All English irregular verbs except “to be” and “to have” are irregular in the same way.

English noun and adjectival forms: Unlike most other European languages, nouns are not more or less arbitrarily divided as being “masculine,” “feminine,” or “neuter.” Adjectives need not change to match noun gender form, nor do they change if a noun is plural.

Written versus spoken forms: Some languages, including French, German, and Greek, among others are very different in their formal written and casual spoken forms. English is not one of these.




	</original>
	<cleaned>
	</cleaned>
	<entity_tagged>
	</entity_tagged>
	<summary>
	</summary>
</comment>
